Tim Carlock



314.719.9051

New York, NY

http://timcarlock.com

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/tscarlock/



Overview

I have over 15 years of engineering and product-development experience, with a particular interest in organizational design, product strategy and user experience. I have sector experience in financial services, consumer tech and business software. I cofounded a software startup where I managed product strategy and development, and I was an early(ish) employee at Uber.

Experience

Engineering Director - Customer Acquisition & Core Experience // Zola // New York, NY February 2020 - April 2020

- Led two teams collectively responsible for customer acquisition and the end-to-end wedding-planning experience.
- Formed and executed a strategy to recharter both teams in order to balance headcount and clarify overall mission and ownership. Working with Product leadership to establish a revised roadmap and backlog for each team.
- Started forming a web-platform team to own and support foundational web-engineering projects across multiple product verticals (e.g., planning tools, registry). This included testing, tooling/builds, deployments and shared code.
- Worked with multiple PMs to establish an improved checkpoint-based process for project management, and overhauled both teams' software-development processes.
- Oversaw an organization of 12 engineers, and managing/mentoring both teams' tech leads and managers.

Engineering Manager, Eats - Restaurant Acquisition // Uber // New York, NY

January 2019 - January 2020

- Leading a product-engineering group consisting of 16 engineers and one engineering manager split across three subteams: accounts platform, sales insights and self-signup (https://www.ubereats.com/restaurant/signup).
- Re-organized the engineering and product teams to increase development velocity, simplify project staffing and create new
 growth and development opportunities for engineers. Along with the Product Manager, I co-developed the team's revised
 vision, strategy, OKRs/KPIs and roadmap.
- Established structure and processes for the team's projects, including a sprint-inspired process and pod-based approach to project staffing.
- Onboarded 11 engineers in the Toronto office and established an interim 6-month roadmap while their product organization was being built out.

Engineering Manager, Developer Experience // Uber // San Francisco, CA

March 2017 - January 2019

- Managed 11 engineers and tech leads across two sub-teams responsible for a portfolio of developer tools and automatedtesting services.
- Worked with Product and Design to maintain a product roadmap, prioritize and plan projects and support an internal user base of 2,600 spread across 90 teams.
- Managed systems and initiatives to streamline manual testing and introduce an organization-wide platform for automated mobile and back-end testing.

Senior Engineer & Tech Lead, Shared Rides // Uber // San Francisco, CA

May 2016 - March 2017

- Technical leader for a team responsible for a variety of internal tools used to streamline and administer the Uber Pool product including mapping/pickup region management, test-trip automation, pricing experimentation and trip visualization.
- · Formed and lead an internal community of web engineers focused on professional development and standards setting.

Senior Engineer & Tech Lead, Uber for Business // Uber // San Francisco, CA

May 2014 - May 2016

- I led the team responsible for building and maintaining the business-facing dashboard of the U4B product.
- Worked closely with Product and Design and managed the prioritization, planning and implementation of a variety of key features including employee management, ride policies and billing.
- Led the effort to migrate the client application from BackboneJS to React and Redux.

Senior Engineer // Learnist // San Francisco, CA

Feb 2013 - May 2014

- I was a full-stack engineer and worked with Ruby on Rails and AngularJS, as well other technologies including CSS3, Sass, CoffeeScript, Redis and Rspec.
- Rebuilt the email-preference-management system including a redesign of the data-storage architecture, authorization and the UI for preference management.
- Rebuilt the content-curation UI and workflow, and created new designs for the primary application views.
- Managed a full migration from server-rendered views to a single page app built on AngularJS.

Software Engineer II // Expedia // San Francisco, CA

May 2012 - Feb 2013

- Developed an API to serve localized hotel reviews for multiple Expedia properties including search and travel packages. The API was developed using Java/Spring and MongoDB and was deployed to EC2.
- Managed deployment and provisioning using Jenkins, Capistrano and Chef.

Co-Founder & Product Lead // Nexly // San Francisco, CA

August 2009 - April 2012

Nexly was a lead-generation and tracking toolset for business-services companies. I was responsible for product strategy and development.

- Worked closely with users to understand key problems and needs, identify features and develop a product roadmap.
- Hired and managed designers and developers and oversaw all aspects of feature development and deployment.
- Developed the application using Rails and PostgreSQL running on Heroku. Front-end technologies included CSS3, jQuery,
 Sass and HAML.

Education

University of Missouri - St Louis // Bachelor of Science - Information Systems

August 2004

Coursework including system architecture, relational databases, OOP and language design and project management.

University of Missouri - St Louis // Bachelor of Science - Finance

January 2003

Coursework including asset pricing & allocation, corporate finance, economic modeling and accounting.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript, Ruby, HTML, CSS/Sass, Java, C#, SQL

Frameworks/Libraries: React, Redux, Ruby on Rails

Tools: Jira, Phabricator, Git, Jenkins, Sketch